XUJIE ZHENG IOS DEVELOPER

z374201743@gmail.com **♀** 55 Bremner Blvd, Toronto, ON M5J0A6

Senior software engineer with 5+ years' experience in architecting scalable web and native mobile solutions, managing development teams and delivering products from an idea to production. Comprehensive knowledge of javascript, swift and CI/CD. Strong background in creating maintainable high load architectures from scratch and refactoring existing systems to match new

Skills

TECH STACK

requirements.

Angular

ReactJS

NodeJS

CSS

PHP

Python

C#

Swift Cocoa

Jenkins

Shell Script

MySQL

MogoDB

PROGRAMMING PRACTICES

Clean Architecture

SOLID Principle

Protocol Oriented Programming

Object Oriented Programming

Test Driven Development

Behaviour Driven Development

MVVM

MVC

Redux

LANGUAGE

Mandarin

Cantonese

Education

Dalhousie University Bachelor Computer and Electrical Engineering 2015

Employment

IBM Canada

Mobile Lead Developer

Halifax, NS

Oct. 2019 to Current

Mar. 2019 to Oct. 2019

Sept. 2010 to Dec. 2015

Led a full-stack agile team to continuously deliver native mobile apps for one of the largest Canadian companies in the airline industry, with more than 500 thousand daily active users. Collaborated with project managers and led the iOS, Android and NodeJS developers. Additionally, contributed to the DevOps automation process for deployment, code scan and source code management.

Halifax, NS

iOS Platform Lead

Designed the architecture of the iOS project by implementing best practices including and not limited to MVVM, protocol-oriented programming, and clean design with the SOLID principal. Led and mentored a team of iOS developers to follow Test Driven Development, and ensure best practice via code reviews. Dived deep into CoreData and implemented background auto-refresh from remote GraphQL services, also utilize CoreDate relationships and various MergePolicies to provide a smooth user experience.

Halifax, NS

Senior Angular Develope

Feb. 2018 to Mar. 2019

Continuously deliver user-demanded features for the mobile app of one of the largest Canadian financial institutions. In return successfully increased the AppStore rating from 2.1 to 4.3. Implemented a Redux favour Angular 2+ hybrid mobile app, with NgRx and RxJS. Collaborated with system admins to simplify the process of showing situational maintenance messages using shell scripts.

WeUsThem

Senior Lead Software Engineer

Sept. 2016 to Dec. 2017

Delivered three award-winning hybrid mobile apps in the healthcare industry. Worked closely with healthcare researchers and the Telus Health development team, to define the features and scope of each project. Implemented Restful APIs middlewares with node.js, C# and python based on the project. Led the angular is mobile team to implement a user-centric solution. Managed and deployed applications to both Apple AppStore and Google Play Store.

Halifax, NS

Software Engineer

Nov. 2015 to Aug. 2016

Developed and maintained multiple websites with WordPress and PHP. Communicated with clients to understand their needs and respond to emerging situations. Developed websites for NSCAD (the most well known Canadian Art School), and campaign websites for Connect2Canada to gather Canadians in the US to celebrate Canada Day. In addition, responsible for maintaining the Customer Relationship Management framework for Connect2Canada.

Dongguan Kaifa Technology Co, .LTD (subsidiary of China Electronics Corporation)

Guangdong, China

Information Technology Support

June 2015 to Aug. 2015

Assisted in establishing the sharing file system in the Windows server. Configured Switch for the inner and outer network of the manufactory. Diagnosed and support for general computer software problems.

Volunteering

Saint Vincent Nursing house

Sept. 2014 to Sept. 2015

Switch open street sundays

July 2013 to Oct. 2013

Supper Nova event

Oct. 2013 to Oct. 2013

Alzheimer Society of NS

Sept. 2010 to Sept. 2010